- My son was imprisoned too.
- Says your son died
of a heart attack.
- There's something
they're not telling me.
- That kid?
He didn't just up and get
in a fight without good reason.
You don't know
what you talking about.
- Look, are the guards corrupt?
- No! He just died!
I need Mike to drop that case.
You telling me
to go back on my word
because your client's
bullying you?
It's one pro Bono.
He can drop it.
If I give you an assignment,
you do it.
Since I got here, I have had
to take shit from Louis.
And now you're asking me
to waste my time
and my ability
on something like this.
We can't have you
setting a precedent
that Alex's clients
can run roughshod all over us.
The only reason
that you're pissed about this
is your new honeysuckle friend
canceled lunch on you for me.
I can't let them get away
with this
without handing it off
to the one lawyer I know
who cares enough
to see this thing through.
If our firm is associated
with that case,
we lose a huge client.
- I'm not working on it.
Then you're gonna put that
in writing and you're gonna
deliver it to Alex's client.
I was just wondering.
Have you redone
the assignment
that Rachel gave you?
Not yet.
I had a ton on my plate.
- You're fired.
What kind of best man
would I be
if I didn't offer for you
to have it here?
Pretty shitty one,
if you ask me.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks, Harvey.
You sure he's not in?
I hate to walk in
on the man
in his tighty-whities.
I don't think Harvey
wears tighty-whities.
Oh, Jesus Christ, Rachel.
I don't wanna think about
what the man wears.
Well...
what do you think?
This is great!
If you're a...
Bachelor pushing 50
and you need to impress
women.
No, no, no, no.
What are you doing?
Don't go in his fridge!
Rachel.
The man gave us his keys.
Trust me.
He knows we're gonna
go through his shit.
So basically you came here
to look at what he eats
and to say that this is
a "no" for the wedding.
Of course it's a no.
But the fact is...
why are we even talking
venue at all
when you don't even
have a date?
We're gonna get around
to that.
Mm-hmm.
Just like you...
got around
to the announcement?
- What?
- Your mother said
that she arranged
for a photographer,
but you cancelled.
Same with the florist.
What's going on?
- Nothing is going on.
Mike and I are both
really busy
getting our careers
off the ground right now.
Rachel, that's just it.
If you can't focus
on your wedding,
how are you gonna
make time to focus
on your marriage?
Now, that's why
you came here, isn't it?
To give me
sweet advice like that.
Well, that, and to tell
the mighty Harvey Specter
I took his toilet bowl
for a test drive.
Dad...you're not
doing that.
You know how to
suck the fun out of
everything, don'tcha?
Oh, my God.
You. Where the hell
is Stephanie?
- She's not here.
- What do you mean,
she's not here?
I just got off the phone
with a client, and she never
filed their motion to dismiss.
- That's because I fired her.
- You what?!
She was the smartest
fourth-year we had!
She was also insubordinate,
and I made a decision.
I don't give a shit
what you made.
She was working for me
on Delta Securities,
and I need her back.
- Okay, Louis,
I'm not getting her back.
What kind of message
does that send
to the other associates?
- Better than the one
we're sending out now
which is that this firm
is a Goddamn joke.
- Louis, you need to calm down
right now before this
goes in the wrong direction,
'cause this isn't about
Stephanie.
This is about Tara
and the fact that you
haven't been dealing with her.
- This has nothing to do
with Tara.
This is about Harvey
running this firm
into the ground.
And how exactly
has he been doing that?
Let me run it down for you.
I'm pissed at him.
Mike's pissed at him.
And the last time I saw you,
you were pissed at him.
So instead of telling me
that you're not gonna hire
Stephanie back,
why don't you go tell
the lord God almighty
that if he is not careful,
he's not gonna have
a kingdom to rule over anymore!
- Morning.
- Harvey, I'm sort of busy,
so if you're here
to shoot the shit--
I'm here
to give you this.
- What's this?
- It's my way of saying thanks.
- For what?
- You know what.
Harvey, I dropped the suit
because you asked me to.
You don't have to give me
anything in return.
Has anyone ever taught you
how to be gracious?
Open the file.
This's a pro Bono.
I figured you didn't
get to complete
your one-for-you this time,
so it's only fair.
Plus, you didn't want me
to sue you
for violating our agreement.
- Doesn't look good
to have Robin coming after
Batman for breach of contract.
Seriously, Mike, I know
how hard that was for you,
and I don't want there
to be any bad blood
between you and Alex.
- I don't have a problem
with Alex, Harvey.
- You sure?
I'm sure.
- Sure?
- Good. Yeah.
- All good?
- You should go.
Let me guess.
You're bored being C.O.O.,
you miss me,
and you want back
on my desk.
I never want back
on your desk, Harvey,
and I'm here to tell you
that your honeymoon
as Managing Partner is over.
Is this about me
not calling a vote
after you undermined me
in that meeting?
I'm gonna let that go
because you need to understand
that right now
people are mad at you.
- Relax, Donna.
I took care of Mike.
- Good for you.
You're one for three.
- Maybe you didn't know this,
but that's good enough to get
you into the Hall of Fame.
You know what, Harvey,
instead of being so arrogant,
maybe you could figure out
a way to keep all of us happy.
Starting with your number two.
- What's that supposed to mean?
It means Louis is out
of his mind at the moment.
You poured fuel on the fire,
and if you asked me
to choose between the two of you
for Managing Partner right now,
I'd choose Alex Williams.
- Donna--
- Listen to me, Harvey.
If making me C.O.O.
wasn't just some
bullshit move
to make me feel good,
you'll get your head
out of your ass,
listen to what
I'm telling you,
and realize
you've got a problem.
♪ See the money,
wanna stay for your meal ♪
♪ Get another piece of pie
for your wife ♪
♪ Everybody wanna know
how it feel ♪
♪ Everybody wanna see
what it's like ♪
♪ I'll even eat a bean pie,
I don't mind ♪
♪ Me and Missy is so busy,
busy making money ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ All step back,
I'm 'bout to dance ♪
♪ Suits 7x04 ♪
Divide and Conquer
Original Air Date on August 2, 2017
♪ The greenback boogie ♪
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
Harvey.
Jessica.
Retirement suits you.
- I'm not retired.
- You look retired.
I look relaxed.
There's a difference.
Now, what's going on,
Harvey?
The last time you flew
to Chicago this often,
Michael was still playing.
I'm in a situation
at the office.
Well, the first thing
to do when you're in trouble
is admit to yourself what you
did to get yourself there.
What do you think I did?
I made a deal with Mike
to come back.
I made Donna a partner
without thinking it through.
I hired someone
against Louis's wishes.
And all those things
are colliding with each other
into a big pile of
"people hate Harvey."
Well, at least it's not
a big pile of
"people hate Jessica."
- That's your advice?
No.
Harvey, my advice is to give
a big piece of new business
to the person least likely
to let anything go.
- Louis.
- Nine times outta ten.
I can't just manufacture
that overnight.
Harvey, do you remember
that time
we poached Trotter Systems
from Zane?
You gotta be shitting me.
That was a prearranged deal?
I worked my ass off
to get Trotter.
You did.
And you completely forgot
that you were pissed at me
about some bullshit
neither one of us
can remember anymore.
- Rook to bishop four.
- Exactly.
Now, take a look at your menu,
'cause I'm starving.
When, exactly,
do you think
I'm gonna stop coming
to you with these things?
The truth is, Harvey,
you don't need to come
to me anymore.
You just do it
'cause you miss me.
Hey. Can I talk to you
for a second?
Yeah. But I only have
a few minutes.
I have court.
I met with my dad at Harvey's
apartment this morning.
Don't tell me.
He said a bachelor pad
is no place for his
special little girl
to celebrate the biggest
day of her life.
Well, Mike,
you have to admit
the only reason
that we changed it
from the Plaza
in the first place
was because we didn't want
the attention.
But now that you're
a legitimate lawyer...
we don't have to worry
about that.
Rachel, it's okay.
I just want you to be happy.
- So you're not mad.
- Not at all.
Good. Because now that
it is at the Plaza,
I called and made an appointment
with the wedding team
for us to go over
some menu options.
Wait, wait, wait.
You made an appointment
in between when I said it
was okay a second ago and now?
Yeah, y-you didn't
just notice me do that?
It was crazy fast!
- You're fast.
Mike, seriously, I appreciate
you being so understanding.
The appointment
is tonight at 7:00.
Rachel, I have a meeting
tonight with my pro Bono,
and I can't put it off.
Can you do this one without me?
Of course I can, but
I wanted us to do it together.
Rachel, listen to me.
I know you...right?
You're gonna have
a thousand questions.
You're gonna want to
narrow down the choices.
I promise you I will be
at every other meeting.
Okay.
I'll take care of it.
- All right. Love you.
- Love you, too.
Why aren't you playing
from the men's tees?
If you're here to insist
that my daughter gets married
in that love shack of yours,
that ship has sailed.
- Oh, I don't care
if she gets married
at the Taj Mahal.
I'm here to take you up
on Jessica's arrangement.
Yeah. What arrangement
was that?
The one
where you do me a favor
and I give you
a big one in return.
What the hell do you think
letting Katrina Bennett
and Company
walk over to you
without a fight was?
I didn't ask you
to do that.
I don't care whether
you asked me or not.
It's been a thin quarter,
and I'm no Goddamn Santa Claus.
- Robert.
- Okay, Harvey.
You want a favor?
I'll give you one.
Instead of you asking me
for a handout,
you should watch your
backside,
because you've got a missile
coming straight for you.
- Bratton Gould.
- Yes. Bratton Gould.
What'd you think
they were gonna do
when you took their senior
partner and marquee client
out from under their noses?
- I knew they'd try
to retaliate, but I didn't think
it would happen this fast.
Well, today's the day.
Let me tell you something.
I have no love for them.
So I'll do whatever
I can to help.
But like I said,
it's been a thin quarter.
And I'm not letting you
get one of my clients.
Oliver.
What are you doing here?
- I need to talk to you.
- If it's about the case,
I can't do that,
and you know it.
- Please, I just need a minute.
- Oliver,
we signed an agreement.
I can't be doing this.
Not to mention
I have other cases.
The guard's testimony
doesn't match
their version of events,
and I can't prove it.
What do you mean?
The prison claims
the doctor was on the premises.
The guard says
they had to call him.
I asked for
surveillance video
to see if he was
already there.
They said they can't
disclose it
because it would violate
HIPAA rules.
Shit.
What about surveillance
of the parking lot?
- They're saying
that footage is gone.
- Then they're definitely
hiding something.
- But I can't prove it.
And if I don't get
something,
I can't move forward
with this case.
Listen, Oliver,
like I said,
I can't discuss this case.
What but what I can
tell you is that
if you can convince someone
that you already have something,
that's the best way
to get them in the room.
I get it--I convince them
I have the doctor's time card,
and he was nowhere near
that place,
I can get them to settle.
- Like I said,
I can't help you.
Good not talking
to you, Mike.
Harvey, we need to talk,
and it can't wait.
Then walk with me, because
Bratton's getting ready
to poach our clients,
and Louis needs to know.
He already knows.
They're making a play
for Delta Securities,
and that's not their only move.
- Don't tell me.
They're coming after
my clients too.
AC Technologies.
But, Harvey,
they're not trying to poach.
They're suing
for patent infringement.
Aw, shit!
Louis, whatever you're doing
to keep Delta Securities,
take a breath.
I need you to listen
to what I have to say.
- Oh, I'm done listening to you.
You wanna manage this firm
into the ground,
you go right ahead.
But when your bullshit
puts one of my biggest
clients on the block,
that's when I'm done
playing good soldier.
Listen to me.
Bratton's not just coming
after our clients--they're
trying to divide and conquer.
What are you, Caesar now?
This isn't the Roman Empire.
I don't care what it is.
You think it's a coincidence
they're forcing you to close
on one of your clients
while suing one of mine
for patent infringement?
You're saying I can't
keep my own clients?
Louis, all he's saying
is you should switch clients
and play to your strengths.
- Pass!
Look, I get it--
you don't want Harvey's help
because you're mad at him.
But the least you can do
is to go Alex.
He came from Bratton.
He knows their playbook.
- I don't need their playbook.
And he's the reason
they're coming after us
in the first place.
- Okay, Louis, do it your way.
But you better be
good and ready,
because Bratton knew enough
to come after a client
you almost lost a year ago
and to sue mine
for something
I don't know anything about.
Which means they've got
someone inside this place
telling them what to do.
Louis, can I talk to you
for a second?
No, you can't, because
right at this moment--
I know, you're gonna
meet Delta Securities.
And Harvey already
made it clear
you don't want my help
trying to keep them.
But I have something--
- No buts, Alex.
I don't want your help.
I don't want whatever you have,
because I don't trust ya.
- Trust me? What the hell
are you talking about?
- For all I know,
you were the one who
gave Bratton
the inside information
on us in the first place.
You know what, Louis,
if you think that,
then why the hell don't you
fire me right now?
If it were up to me,
Alex, I would.
Your Honor,
I don't care what they say.
We filed our patent
before they did.
Well, beating
someone off the line
doesn't mean that you didn't
jump the gun to do it.
And our losses
are growing by the day.
Mr. Specter, you'll have your
chance to refute him at trial.
All right, listen,
you want me to be honest?
I haven't felt
prioritized lately.
Are you kidding me?
Who was there when you
had to restructure in '07?
Not to mention,
I just saved your ass last year.
And that was then.
And now I feel like
I can't even get you
on the phone anymore.
- Your Honor--
- That's enough.
I find the evidence
Mr. Walsh is presenting
compelling enough
to let this go forward.
There's only one problem
with that, Your Honor.
We just took one of
their partners,
all of his clients.
They're pissed about it,
and now they want
some get-back.
You being willing
to give me your phone number
isn't the point, Louis.
- Well, it should be.
- Who are you?
- This is Alex Williams,
our newest senior partner, and
he was just stopping by. Alex--
I'm not just the newest
senior partner, Tim.
I'm also the partner
that Bratton Gould just lost.
Your Honor,
they entered into
a fee-waiving partnership
agreement yesterday
with a company that's suddenly
claiming infringement
against
one of our clients today.
Your Honor, their client
caused real damages.
If that's true, those damages
will still be there
in eight weeks,
which means the only reason
you'd be upset right now
is if this action is nonsense.
So which is it--
eight weeks or drop the case?
Morelli's expense reports for
the last three years.
The guy spends
more time in Vegas
than David Blaine.
And now you know.
Just like you already know
that Louis kills
for you out there
whether he's taking
your calls or not.
I'll call you tomorrow
about the acquisition, Louis.
Thank you, Tim.
Nice move, finding out about
that partnership agreement.
Nice move telling
our client
he's not gonna be billed
for last quarter.
Nothing eases the pain
of a bullshit lawsuit
like cash in your pocket.
- Speaking of which,
I've been back at work
for three weeks now.
Thinking it's time
I got a raise.
Easy, tiger.
Mike, seriously,
I thought you were busy
with that pro Bono.
I am. Donna said
you needed my help,
so...I gave it to you.
Thanks, Robin.
Ah, you're welcome, Batman.
Louis, really...
you didn't have to do this.
- What, are you kidding?
You saved me
after I was an asshole.
You didn't have to do that.
- Yes, I did.
Because I don't care
how you acted.
We're all
in the same boat now.
I guess we are.
Boy, you really...have no
love for your old firm, do you?
If I'm being truthful
with you,
I was never gonna get
where I wanted to be
as long as I was there.
- Name partner.
You know, I thought of
leaving Pearson Hardman
at one point.
- Bullshit.
No, it's the truth.
I even got a headhunter
and everything.
- I thought you loved it there.
- I do.
Doesn't mean
that I didn't feel
unappreciated and overlooked.
I find it hard to believe
anyone could overlook you.
Well, they did,
and I got to thinking...
I can be the best
lawyer in the world, and...
it won't change
how they see me.
Like you must have been
out sick or something
the day the name partner gods
came down
saying who's gonna make it
up the God damn mountain.
That's exactly right,
and it turns out
I wasn't sick that day,
and neither were you.
And if you ever
feel overlooked again,
I would hope that
you can come to me
so I can help fix it.
Means a lot to me, Louis.
Well...
like you said...
We're all in the same
boat now.
Rachel, do you have
a minute?
I need your help.
- Yeah, of course.
What's going on?
- I think Stephanie Patel
may be helping Bratton
poach our clients.
What? Since when
is Stephanie at Bratton?
Since this morning,
and it's a long story,
but someone gave them
inside information about us,
and given
that she just started...
I need you to go over
there,
and I need you
to get her to stop.
Me? How am I supposed
to do that?
I don't care if it means
offering her her job back.
But whatever it is,
it has to happen tonight.
Wait, Donna, you can't
be serious right now.
- It's the only way that we--
- Donna, Louis eviscerated her,
and you fired her.
There's no way
she's ever coming back here.
You don't know that.
Not to mention the fact that
I have a meeting this evening
with the wedding planner, so--
I don't care
what you have tonight.
We need to do something,
and we need to do it now.
Okay.
What's going on?
Harvey took a chance
on me, Rachel.
He went out on a limb,
and now I have been
promoted to a position
that people think
I'm not ready for.
I didn't mean it
when I said that.
I know that.
But if one of the
first things I did ends up
giving Bratton
a roadmap to picking
this firm apart,
I will never forgive
myself.
And Stephanie might not
talk to you,
but I know
she won't talk to me.
Okay.
I'll go see her, Donna.
Anything else you
want me to fix for you
before I get back to my case?
- I'll let you know
after I see Louis.
- What do you mean?
I mean if he couldn't
stop Bratton
from poaching his client,
us doing what we just did
only gives us a split decision.
- But you said Louis
made it clear
he doesn't want your help.
He may not want it,
but if that shit's
not taken care of,
he's getting it whether
he likes it or not.
Louis, before you jump
down my throat again--
Relax, Harvey, I'm not
upset with you anymore.
In fact, I even came to
an agreement with Alex
after he locked up
Delta Securities.
- Good.
- What about you?
Do you need my help
with your lawsuit?
It's taken care of.
Don't tell him I said this,
but Mike jumped inside
his phone booth
and put on his Superman
outfit.
Oh, that's great.
So I guess...
this means there's only one
thing left for you to do.
Well, I'd say there's only
one thing left for us to do.
You want me to go
with you?
Your name's up on that
wall, isn't it?
I see you got
your own office.
What are you doing here?
I know that you didn't
feel valued at Pearson Specter,
and I wanted to apologize
for my part in that.
I also just--I wanted you
to know
that it was never my intention
to get you fired.
I hope you're not here
to offer me my job back.
- And what if I said I was?
- I'd say I wouldn't take it.
Okay...
in that case,
I am here to find out
if you're giving your new firm
privileged information.
Let me get this straight.
You have...the nerve
to fire me
and then come here
and accuse me
of breaking
attorney-client privilege?
How else is your firm
getting so much information
on our on-going cases?
- You think I'm the only person
with a grudge
against your firm?
Harvey Specter
declared war on this place
long before I got here.
And not only am I not
giving them information,
they don't need my help,
and they didn't ask for my help.
Just to be clear, Stephanie,
you've lied to me before.
And breaking attorney-client
privilege
is a dis-barrable offense,
and if we find out
that's what's been
happening here--
- No, Rachel,
I didn't lie to you.
Like you said,
I used a loophole.
'Cause I'm a good lawyer,
and I'm also an ethical lawyer.
So if this firm is getting
inside information
from Pearson Specter,
they're not getting it
from me.
Hey, Mike, wait up.
Oliver, what are you
doing here?
I was just waiting for you
so we can grab that beer
like we talked about.
- Except we didn't
talk about grabbing--
- Just walk with me.
God damn it, Oliver,
I told you--
- Mike, relax.
It's over.
The bluff worked.
What do you mean,
it worked?
I got a number,
and it's good.
Shit.
What?
This offer's not just good.
It's too good.
What're you talking about?
You think they're not gonna pay?
- I mean this isn't
the number you give
to make someone go away.
It's a number you give when
you need them to go away.
You're saying you think
there's more cases
like this out there.
- I'm saying that when
someone acts like this,
there's more to find.
Which means you need
to convince Mr. Reyes
to turn this down
and keep looking.
Are you serious, Mike?
This is more money
than this family's ever seen.
- And you convince them--
What? That I'm gonna
find all those other cases?
I already bluffed 'em
once, Mike.
And the only reason we were
able to make this case
is because we threatened
to sue them
over a specific guy.
- Then knock on the door
of everyone that has come
out of that place
and find more guys.
- Mike...
If there are other
victims out there,
I feel for them.
But I'm representing Oscar.
He's suffering.
And I don't feel right
telling him not to do this.
So if you want this done,
you're gonna have to
do it yourself.
Rachel, please tell me
that you got her to back off.
- It wasn't her.
- What do you mean,
it wasn't her?
It had to be her.
Donna, I apologized to her.
I threatened her,
and I cajoled her.
Trust me--it wasn't her.
Rachel...look,
I didn't mean that stuff
that I said before about not
caring about your appointment.
- I know.
- Well, did you make it?
'Cause I'd hate to think
you missed it for nothing.
I'm walking in right now.
Don't worry.
I'm right on time.
Hi. I'm so sorry.
Rachel Zane.
Deborah Kaplan.
Did my assistant
give you the wrong time?
Because I had us down
for 7:00.
And it's almost 8:00.
I know.
I had an emergency at work,
and it couldn't wait.
But my understanding was
it's a two-hour appointment.
So I was just hoping
that we could
go over as much as possible.
- Of course.
The truth is, I usually
take the first hour
to offer you a glass
of champagne
and try to get to
know you anyway.
But the champagne
is still cold,
and we can just
dive right in.
You still double-billing
to pay for that house
in the Hamptons?
No. I'm working late
to pay for it.
And the one in Vail
and the apartment in Paris.
That's a lotta homes.
Sounds like a man
who's compensating.
So how're you doing, Harvey?
- Oh, he's doing great.
'Cause we just shut down your
pathetic assault on our firm.
- Is that so?
- You're Goddamn right,
that's so.
Then might I ask what exactly
are you doing here?
We're here to tell you
that if you try this shit
again,
the same thing's gonna happen,
only next time,
we won't just play defense.
We'll hit you with
a tortious interference suit
in the neighborhood
of a billion dollars.
Well, you better get ready,
'cause next time...
starts right now.
What, are you kidding?
You already threw
everything you had at us once.
Didn't make a dent.
- Not everything.
By tomorrow morning, I'll be
poaching 20 of your clients,
and I'll be suing
another 20 of his.
And that little trick
you played
in the courtroom today?
It isn't going to
work tomorrow.
- Tom, you made your point.
You're pissed off
that we brought Alex over,
but this doesn't have to--
- I don't give two shits
about Alex Williams.
Lawyers grow on Goddamn trees.
I want my clients back,
and I want the 30 million
in billables
that come along with them,
hand-delivered...by you.
- That's never gonna happen.
- What do you think, Harvey?
Do you think that's
"never gonna happen"?
Like I said,
whatever you throw at us,
we'll throw it
right the hell back.
With what manpower?
You wanna pick a fight
with a little
regional law firm
to flex your muscles,
go ahead.
But we're five times
your size.
This is a fight you started.
And this is a fight
that you cannot win.
So you give me back
my clients,
or your legacy
at Pearson Specter Litt
is going to be
that you were the one
that put them in the ground.
Let me get this straight.
I got an offer for more money
than I'll see my whole life,
and you want me
to turn it down
based on a feeling that
whatever happened to Chris
happened to other people?
- It's not a feeling.
It's an instinct
that comes from
working on hundreds
of cases like this.
And if you take this deal,
you're never gonna get
the answers you want.
You'll never know
what happened to your son.
And I have another son
and two daughters,
and this changes
their lives.
- Mr. Reyes--
- Are you telling me
that you can prove
they had something to do
with my son's death?
Yes. I believe
that Oliver can get enough to--
- No, not Oliver.
You. Because you're the one
who took my case,
and then you backed out.
- I told you,
there was a conflict.
- I don't know what that means.
Then listen to me
right now.
I know that you know my parents
died in a car accident.
But what you don't know
is that after they did,
a lawyer...came to my
grandmother
and made her an offer.
She took it,
instead of going to court.
And I am telling you,
she regretted that
for the rest of her life.
Oscar, there's no price
that'll make the pain go away.
Then what will?
Doing everything you can
to make sure no one else
ever has to feel it too.
At least, that's the closest
I've ever gotten.
And you think
turning this down will do that.
I think Chris is gone and
we can't ever bring him back.
Which means this is about
more than just money
or justice.
It's about stopping other
people like him from dying.
And I think it can be done,
but...
even if it can't...
we gotta try.
Tell them no.
- Harvey, how'd it go?
- Listen to me.
I didn't think it mattered
before,
but they've got someone
feeding them inside information.
I need to know who it is.
I'm already working
on it, Harvey.
Good. 'Cause this is your
chance to prove to everybody
I made the right decision
giving you that promotion.
Robert.
We need to talk.
- From what I hear,
you need to spend
less time talking
and more time looking over
your firm.
And you said if I needed
help doing that to let you know.
All right.
Let's have it.
What do you need?
It's nothing you haven't
proposed to Jessica before.
You gotta be kidding me.
You want to merge?
I'm not talking about
a real merger.
I'm talking about
putting out word
that two of the best firms
in the city
are now one of the biggest
firms in the city.
You don't have the manpower
to fight him, do you?
Bratton's making this
an arms race, Robert.
If I don't have the numbers
to fight a war,
I have to at least
make it look like I do.
- I can't do it, Harvey.
- Robert, it's a bluff.
A bluff with nothing
but downside for me.
That's not true.
When this is over,
you can have your pick
of the clients
that came over from Bratton.
- When this is over,
I'm gonna look like
I backed away from a merger,
that I can't be trusted,
not to mention
that I look like I'm so weak
that I needed to merge with
a struggling firm like yours
to begin with.
- Is that what you think
we are--struggling?
- Harvey...
you need me to answer
that...
then you've got an even bigger
problem than Tommy Bratton.
Harvey, please tell me Zane
went for the merger idea.
- He didn't.
- Damn it! We're gonna drown
without any help.
- Then we'll get help.
What do you think
we've been working on?
I thought you were trying
to find the leak.
- We were, but we can't.
- And since Zane might say no,
I put out some feelers
with headhunters
to see about getting some
first-years and paralegals.
The problem is, we need
a minimum of 2 dozen each
to handle the workload,
but it's gonna run us
over 3 million a year.
- Then we'll get a bridge loan
from your guy at Fidelity.
- We already used
that line of credit last year
when we expanded the 42nd floor.
- Shit.
- Harvey, what the hell
are we gonna do?
I don't see a way out of this.
- I have a way out.
Give them what they want.
I'm not giving up
your clients, Alex.
I do that, I might as well
let you go.
Then let me go,
because I'm not gonna
be responsible
for driving you in the ground.
- No, I'm not gonna do that.
- Why the hell not?
Because you're one of us now.
And I agree.
Well, what are we
gonna do?
You're gonna go back
to finding out
who's feeding them
inside information,
and you two
are gonna figure out
who they're coming after
first.
And I'm gonna figure out how to
beat this son of a bitch.
Mike, hey.
How'd it go?
- He turned the offer down.
- Thank God.
I thought you'd be
disappointed.
That was before
I found this...
and this...
and this.
- Holy shit.
- You were right.
As soon as I started
looking in the right places,
all the apples started
falling from the tree.
There's gotta be
at least 20 complaints
of prisoners being denied
their release date.
And every one of them
involves injuries
and some kind of vague
disciplinary action.
Jesus. They're not just
cheaping out on medical care.
They're manufacturing revenue.
Oliver, this...
This is unbelievable.
You got a class now.
There's only one problem.
I don't have the resources
to handle this alone.
Oliver, we've been
over this.
I signed an agreement
that said I wouldn't touch it.
I can't cross that line.
- Jesus Christ, Mike.
You're telling me you care
more about some
piece of paper you signed
than about these men's lives?
No, I don't,
but I signed it.
Which means if I get involved
and they find out,
the case gets tossed,
and Oscar gets nothing.
You lived a lie for years.
You're telling me
you can't keep a secret
about working one Goddamn case?
- I gave Harvey my word.
- So what the hell
am I supposed to do?
- You're supposed to
convince Nathan to give you
the resources to pursue this.
And when I can't and I have to
go back and tell Oscar
that we can't
move forward with this...
that's gonna be on you.
I know how to
take down Bratton.
Alex,
we've been over this.
I am not giving up you
or your clients.
I'm not talking about that.
I got something on him.
Why is this the first
I'm hearing about this?
You know why.
Because whatever it is,
he's got the same
damn thing on you.
Son of a bitch.
You should have told me
this before.
I couldn't.
You never would've hired me.
I meant when they started
coming after us.
I was hoping I wouldn't
have to use it.
Well, now I do.
What is it?
- I can't tell you.
- Are you kidding me?
As long as I don't tell you,
you're not party to it.
I'm not gonna expose you
like that.
I'm gonna take care
of this myself.
If you're gonna do that,
then why are you even
coming to me?
Because you took me in.
I'm a part of this firm now,
and if I do this, I'm not
sure what's gonna come of it.
That's not good enough.
You go over there and do this,
you sure as hell
better make it work.
All right, good.
We'll wrap this up tomorrow.
Thanks.
I was wondering when
you'd come crawling back.
I'm back,
but I'm not crawling.
I'm here to tell you
you're backing the hell off
my firm.
I know what you're here to do,
but let me ask you this.
Does your firm know what it is
that you did?
No. But if you don't
let this shit go,
they're not gonna be
the only ones I tell.
And not just what I did.
What you did.
I let this shit go,
and it comes back
and hits you in the ass.
You're gonna sign something
saying I had
nothing to do with this.
I already did.
Just like I also prepared
something for you to sign
saying you won't so much
as look at any of our clients
for the next ten years.
- You're willing to do this.
- Like I said.
I already did it.
It's on you now.
Yes. It is.
Is it done?
What do you think?
I think you probably
went in there
and said something like, "You're
gonna drop these lawsuits
"and you're gonna forget
about coming after
any of our clients."
And he said, "Our clients?
Don't you mean my clients?"
And I said, "No,
motherfu--er, I don't.
"Because I'm at
Pearson Specter now,
and he's not getting
my clients."
You're twice the man
he is, Alex.
- What do you mean?
- I mean if the ship
were sinking, Tommy Bratton
would throw his best friend
overboard
to get himself to shore.
You, on the other hand,
would offer him a life raft.
Thanks, Harvey.
No, Alex.
Thank you.
Hey...
what are we gonna tell
Louis and Donna
about how this all went away?
We're gonna tell them
we did whatever it took.
And for the record,
Louis is right.
You are one of us now.
Don't tell Louis
I said he was right.
Don't worry about it.
I only listen to
every third thing you say
anyway.
Hey.
- Hey.
- I just realized I never
asked how the meeting
at the Plaza went.
Um...
I canceled it.
- I don't understand.
- I got there late,
and the woman started
showing me options anyway.
But I realized...
I was spending more time
thinking about
who was feeding Bratton Gould
inside information
than I was about
what color our napkins
were going to be.
So you don't wanna have it
at the Plaza anymore?
No, that's not it.
Mike, what's wrong with us?
We can't even find the time
to keep one appointment.
Rachel, come on, our schedules
are crazy right now.
And that's exactly what I told
my dad when he brought it up.
Brought what up?
He said that if we can't make
time for each other right now,
how are we gonna
make time for our marriage?
Hey.
You are the most
important thing in my life.
If you wanna
drop everything right now
and plan the wedding
and the honeymoon
and start picking out
baby names,
then that's what
we'll do.
That's the thing.
I don't wanna drop
everything right now.
I wanna get married...
but I also really care
about what I do.
Maybe your father's right.
- Mike--
- No, I mean that he's right
about how hard it is for us
to throw ourselves
into our wedding right now,
but...
he's wrong if he thinks
we never will.
- What does that mean?
- That means
that I care about
what I do too.
And right now I gotta
go take care of something
that I should have
taken care of before, but...
when we get home,
we're gonna crack open
a bottle of wine,
and we're gonna talk
all night
about the kind of wedding
we wanna have.
And then we are gonna
pick a date.
Really?
Really.
Harvey, I know you're
coming in here to--
Donna, relax.
I came over here to tell you
that it's over.
Why don't you go home
and get some rest?
I know you've been working
around the clock on this thing.
I'm sorry, Harvey.
- What do you mean?
- You promoted me.
You had faith in me,
and I never found out
who it was--I let you down.
Donna, you haven't
let me down in 12 years,
and you didn't start now.
Besides, whoever it was...
doesn't matter anymore.
Hello?
It was you, wasn't it?
What was me?
Don't bullshit me, Jessica.
You called Tommy Bratton
and gave him the roadmap
to me and Louis,
and I wanna know why.
If you figured that out,
then you already know why.
- I want an answer.
You came to me saying
that your house was divided.
And whether you like
hearing it or not, Harvey,
nothing unites a divided house
like an attack from the outside.
That doesn't mean you pick up
the phone and call him.
I didn't call him.
He called me.
He was coming anyway, Harvey.
All I did was mention that...
I didn't like the way
I was treated
on my way out the door,
and if he wanted
to get to you,
he should play you
against Louis.
Jessica, I called you
for advice,
not so that you'd
go behind the scenes
and manipulate things.
- Harvey.
- You said I was ready.
- You are.
And now they know you are,
and they're behind you
for the next time.
- I guess I should thank you.
- You're welcome, Harvey.
But you pull something
like this again...
I won't have to.
Good night, Jessica.
Good night, Harvey.
- Well, look who it is.
- What are you doing?
Just getting ready
for trial tomorrow.
It never stops, does it?
- What's that?
- The work of being a lawyer.
Doesn't mean you
can't make time for...
The more important things.
- Speaking of the more
important things--I set
a meeting with the planner
at the Plaza.
It's gonna be wonderful.
Thank you.
Aw, you don't have to
thank me, Rachel.
All I want is for your wedding
to be exactly what you want.
And what I want
is gonna take some time,
because, Dad, you were right.
I want to...enjoy it
and make time for it.
So Mike and I
are gonna set a date,
but it's not gonna be
for a while.
Well, it doesn't matter
when it is.
As long as you're happy.
Good. Because there's
something else I wanted to say.
I heard this idea
of a fake merger
between us was floated.
- Let me guess.
You think I should have
helped Harvey out.
No. What I was gonna say
was even though it was fake,
I got kind of excited about the
thought of working with my dad.
I never thought
I'd ever hear you say that.
Well, Katrina told me
that you said something once
that I was afraid
I'd never hear, and...
It meant everything to me.
And what's that?
That you think
I'm a great lawyer.
And that you're proud of me.
Rachel...
I may not say it often enough.
But I think it all the time.
I love you, Dad.
I love you too, baby.
- Hello.
- Oliver, it's me.
Sorry, Mike,
I can't talk right now.
I'm kinda busy being overwhelmed
by a case I can't handle.
I take it you couldn't
convince Nathan
to get you more people?
- No. I couldn't.
Well, in that case...
I'm in.
What about your promise
to Harvey?
You let me worry
about Harvey.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man